Guide to the Jerry Retzloff Collection
The Wittliff Collections
- Memorabilia
  - Matchbooks and rolling paper
    - Doug Weston's Troubadour, Los Angeles, CA (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Hall of Fame Motor Inn [Nashville] (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Beverly Hills Hotel, CA (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Guitar picks, 2008, undated
    - CDB [Charlie Daniels Band] (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Willie's Fourth of July Weekend (red w/gold), 2008 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Willie's Fourth of July Weekend (white w/blue), 2008 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Willie's Fourth of July Weekend (white w/red), 2008 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Kinky Friedman (blue w/ white) (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Rings (2): Armadillo ring and plain gold ring (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Audiocassettes
    - Willie Nelson Picnic, Vol 1: Rusty Weir, Greasy Wheels, Willia Alan Ramsey (Box 9)
    - Willie Nelson Picnic, Vol 2: B.W. Stevenson, Michael Murphy (Box 9)
    - Willie Nelson Picnic, Vol 3: Willie Nelson (Box 9)
    - Freda / Alvin Crow at One Knite (Box 9)
    - D.K. Little (Moon Pie) / Storm's 3rd at One Knite (Box 9)
    - Six Pak commercial audiocassette (Box 9)
    - Flatlanders. Side A: Album / Side B: Live Possibly at One Knite (Box 9)
- Oversized Materials
  The Oversized Materials series contains larger format photographs, Lone Star Beer articles and advertisements, posters (including several for Willie Nelson concerts), album covers, and a scrapbook.
  - Scrapbook for a Texas Declaration of Independence event (Box 10)
  - Oversized photographs
    - Group photographs (3 copies) (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Lone Star advertising (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Janet Quist (model) (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Framed Items
    - Kinky Friedman with cigar and Lone Star beer can. Inscribed: "Reverend & Sally – God Love you folks. Thanks for bein' an American. Fondly, Kinky" [8" x 10"] (Box 14)
    - Ggroup with Lone Star beer bottles. black/white ]9" x 14"] (Box 14)
    - Willie Nelson Spirit [inscribed] ]8" x 10"] (Box 14)
    - Willie Nelson collage: Framed newspaper photograph of Nelson. Taped to the outside of the frame: Willie Nelson guitar pick, a sticker name tag from the 1974 July 4th picnic, a 2013 Willie Nelson & Family wristband, and a Record World clipping about Redheaded Stranger. [12" x 15"] (Box 14)
    - Willie Nelson on stage with Lone Star beer sign. Taped to the outside of the frame: Willie Nelson & Family wristbands from 2010, 2011, and 2013 [12" x 15"] (Box 14)
    - Blond woman drinking from a plastic Lone Star beer cup [5" x 7"] (Box 14)
  - Lone Star Beer – Articles about, and Print Advertisements, 1975-1978, undated
    - "For the Good Times" Full page ad, The Action, , November 1975 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - "The Best of Company" Full page ad, The Action [Featuring Willie Nelson ], September 1976 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Full page ad, The Action [beer cans on river], September 1977 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - "No Place But Texas" Full page ad, Action Magazine [artwork by Sam Yeates], March 1978 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - All About Beer, vol 1, no. 4. published by the Beer Drinker's Intl., Inc. Includes article, "Lone Star Beer: The 98 Per Cent Solution" by Bruce Lorange and full page ad on page 7 with artwork by Yeates (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Austin Sun, Vol. 1, No. 15. [Lone Star ad on back featuring B.W. Stevenson, Rusty Wier, and Steve Fromholz for the Cross Country Music Specials] Cover sheets only, April 3, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Austin Sun, Vol. 1, No. 27. [Lone star ad on back featuring Ray Benson], September 19, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Austin Sun. Interior pages only [Lone Star ads with artwork by Sam Yeates], December 16. 1977 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Texas Sun, September 17, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Iconoclast. "Lone Star Gambles to Win Texas Music", September 6, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Iconoclast. "Lone Star Bottles Beer Drinking Music", August 30, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Album covers
    - Six Pack, Vol. 1 featuring Willie Nelson, Ray Wylie Hubbard, Cooder Browne, Don Bowman, Steve Fromholz, and Geezinslaw Brothers. Lone Star Records (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Red Headed Stranger, Willie Nelson. [inscribed, signed] (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Redneck Mothers (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Juz Love dem ol' Greezy Wheels [cover art by Jim Franklin] (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Urban Cowboy Original Motion Picture Soundtrack (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Posters, 1974-1981, undated
    - Continental Club calendar [11" x 17"], December 1981 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Kinky Friedman. Rockefeller's Night Club, Houston. November 20- 21, no year. [Inscribed to Jerry & Sally], [11" x 17"] (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Kinky Friedman "Invasion of the Killer Jews" Austin Opry House. Artwork by Micael Priest [11" x 17"], October 31, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Michael Murphey. Cedar Frost – Armadillo Headquarters. Artwork by Jim Franklin. [11" x 17"], March 22-23, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Austin's First Spring Concert, Bull Creek Party Barn. Artwork by Kerry Awn. [11" x 17"], 1974 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Stormy Monday. One Knite Dive Bar, [11" x 17"]. March 11, no year (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Willie Nelson Posters, 1974-2002, undated
    - Pineywoods Country Festival, April 6 & 7, no year. [8.5" x 11"] (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Tribute to Cosmic Cowboys. Benefit concert. Artwork by Micael Priest [8.5" x 11"], February 10, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - "A Big Willie at the One Knite" Artwork by [GOlliver] 2 copies – one on cream, one on green [11" x 17"], December 15, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - "Willie Nelson Show" Bull Creek Party Barn. [11" x 17"] May 27, no year (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Willie Nelson with Billy Joe Shaver, Milton Carroll, and Geezinslaws Brothers. Bull Creek Party Barn. [11" x 17"] May 27, no year (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - "Second Annual Fourth of July Picnic" College Station at the Texas World Speedway. Artwork by [Boo Thomas Byerly] 2 copies [11" x 17"], July 4, 5, and 6, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Willie Nelson with Geronimo Trevino. John T. Floore Country Store. 2 copies [11" x 17"], April 2, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Jim Franklin calendar, 1976
- Newspapers and Magazines
  Newspapers and magazines are divided between those relating to Willie Nelson, and other music publications.
  - Newspapers and magazines related to Willie Nelson, 1974-2003
    - Billboard, June 16, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Country Music, February 1976 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Cream, February 1976 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Life. [cover and article only], August 1983 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Life, April 1985 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Newsweek, August 14, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Record World, March 6, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - The Texas Flyer Parade, April 1974 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Texas Monthly Birthday Tribute to Willie, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Texas Music, May 1976 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Texas Music, Spring 2003 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Willie's World [Willie Nelson Fan Club], Spring 2003 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - San Antonio Star, January 8, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Southern Voice. "Everything you Wanted to Know about Willie Nelson's 4th of July Picnic but Didn't Know Who to Ask", June 28, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Weekender [San Antonio Express News], January 6, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Austin Notes. Willie and Waylon Open the Austin Opry House", July 1977 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Sunday. "A Visit with Willie Nelson's Momma and Poppa", September 5, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Austin American Statesman insert: Austin Music: Progressive Country (2 copies), July 14, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Clippings relating to Willie Nelson (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Clippings relating to Music and Performers (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Music Magazines and Newspapers, 1975-2002
    - AARP Modern Maturity, September/October, 2002 (Box 12)
    - Austin Sun, Vol. 1, No. 14. [Death of artists Ken Featherston] (2 copies), November 14, 1975 (Box 12)
    - Austin Sun, Vol 1, No. 17. [Kinky Friedman on cover; Lone Star ad featuring Craig Hills on back cover], May 1, 1975 (Box 12)
    - Billboard, October 1, 1975 (Box 12)
    - Billboard, December 20, 1980 (Box 12)
    - Billboard, December 25, 1982 (Box 12)
    - Billboard Spotlight: The First Century, 1877-1977 (Box 12)
    - Buddy, February 1975 (Box 12)
    - Circus, August 31, 1978 (Box 12)
    - Country Music, December 1975 (Box 12)
    - Country Music [no cover], September 1981 (Box 12)
    - Country Rambler, December 2, 1976 (Box 12)
    - Country Song Roundup, December 1976 (Box 12)
    - Entertainment Weekly, November 1993 (Box 12)
    - Hit Parade, April 1976 (Box 12)
    - Iconoclast, February 21, 1975 (Box 12)
    - Iconoclast, April 26, 1974 (Box 12)
    - Iconoclast, November 14, 1975 (Box 12)
    - Images, August 9, 1976 (Box 12)
    - Pearl, March 1975 (Box 12)
    - Pearl "Texas Beer Trilogy", October 1974 (Box 12)
    - Rocky Mountain Music Express. Lone Star ad on back featuring Merle Haggard], May 1978 (Box 12)
    - Texas Monthly, May 1973 (Box 12)
    - Texas Monthly, February 1982 (Box 12)
    - Texas Monthly, May 2000 (Box 12)
    - Texas Music, June 1976 (Box 12)
    - Texas Sun. [Lone star ad on back: Travis County Waterways map], April 15, [1977] (Box 12)
    - Texas Sun, March 25, [1977] (Box 12)
  - Oversized photo of Willie Nelson's TV Guide Cover portrait. 2 framed photographs (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Oversized newspapers
    - Newspapers relating to Willie Nelson (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Daily Texan newspapers (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Nashville Banner newspapers (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Tennessean newspapers (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper clippings relating to music (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Clothing, accessories, and other promotional items
  The bulk of this series is a variety of artist t-shirts. Also included are a number of hats.
  - 5 ceramic coasters with photographs of venues [Poodie's Hilltop, Luckenback P.O., The Continental Club, The Hole in the Wall, & Willie Way street sign], circa 2013 (Box 14)
  - Foam drink koozie, "Compliments of Texas Hatters" in remembrance of the first annual second signing of the Texas Declaration of Independence (Box 14)
  - Clothing
    - One Knite Dive & Tavern T-shirt. White (Box 15)
    - One Knite, "The dive too tough to die" T-shirt. White (Box 15)
    - Willie Nelson: Roll Me up and Smoke Me. T-shirt. Yellow/Green (Box 15)
    - Willie Nelson Running Society T-shirt. White (Box 15)
    - "Proud to be a Jew" The Kinky Experiment T-shirt (Box 15)
    - Lone Star Texas Music Special: Longnecks Love Luckenbach T-shirt (Box 15)
    - First Funseekers Fourth Frolic T-shirt. Purple (Box 15)
    - Charlie Daniels band Volunteers short-sleeved Henley. White (Box 15)
    - Willie Nelson & Family on the Road Again. Satin jacket with "Jerry" embroidered on front. Black (Box 15)
    - Lone Star beer "Sidekick" embroidered satin jacket with "Jerry" on front. Orange (Box 15)
    - Funseekers satin jacket with "Jerry" on front. Red (Box 15)
    - Lone Star hat band from Texas Hatters. Leather [cracked] (Box 15)
    - Leather belt with Lone Star belt buckle (Box 15)
    - Willie Nelson bandana. Red. [2 versions] (Box 15)
    - Willie bandana. Blue (Box 15)
  - Straw hat with Lone Star hat band and "Willie Nelson Family" badge pinned to it. Crushed and with some tears (Box 16)
  - Lone Star "Dude" hat (tan) by Master Hatters of Texas sold in Texas Monthly magazine. Felt with leather Lone Star hatband (Box 17)
  - Light grey cowboy hat with Lone Star pin [Master Hatters?] (Box 18)
  - Grey felt hat with woven hat band belonging to Stan Retzloff (Box 19)
  - Black suede hat with braided band similar to one Willie Nelson wore (Box 20)
  - Blue Paia Maui [Nelson home in Hawaii] baseball cap inscribed "To Jerry Love Willie Nelson, 2009" (Box 20)
- Posters
  Music posters, plus a signed political sign for Kinky Friedman.
  - Proposed Revision to the Texas Declaration of Independence (6) (Map-case Dr. 25)
  - Willie Nelson – Live Broadcast from the Troubadour (Map-case Dr. 25)
  - Third Annual Country Music Jamboree, May 1, 1976 (Map-case Dr. 25)
  - Neil Young / Hawks & Doves (Map-case Dr. 25)
  - Neil Young / Comes a Time (Map-case Dr. 25)
  - Lone Star: Schooner in a Long Neck [artwork by Jim Franklin] (2) (Map-case Dr. 25)
  - Lone Star: Texas Gold [artwork by Jim Franklin] (Map-case Dr. 25)
  - Texas Gold [without the Lone Star ad text] (Map-case Dr. 25)
  - Lone Star: Long Live Long Necks [artwork by Jim Franklin] (Map-case Dr. 25)
  - Elect Richard "Kinky" Friedman Justice of the Peace, Pct 1. [inscribed, signed], May 3 1986 (Map-case Dr. 25)
  - The final goodbye of the legendary One Knite, 2013 (Map-case Dr. 25)
- Framed Items
  - "25 Years with a Bullet" framed record, Feb. 8, 1989 (Frame Annex B 6-B-2)
  - Photograph of Willie Nelson Performing at Bull Creek, 1974 (Frame Annex B 6-B-2)
  - "A Proposed Revision of the Texas Declaration of Independence" [signed] (Frame Annex B 6-B-3)
  - Oil painting of the signing of the Texas Declaration of Independence, Sam Yeates (Frame Annex B 6-B-3)
  - Willie Nelson's 8th annual Fourth of July Picnic, 18 x 28
  - Charlie Daniels Band album cover [inscribed] and fiddle bow, 32 x 23
- Artifacts
  - Silver metal case with bumper stickers
  - Retzloff's brown leather briefcase with bumper stickers
  - Black trunk "Fragile: Sound Equipment (Roll-storage Annex B)
  - "Jerry's Den of Dis & Dat" wooden paddle